<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2019-2020 Alberto Mardegan <info@mardy.it> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>it.mardy.mappero-geotagger</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <name>Mappero Geotagger</name>
  <summary>Add location information to image files</summary>

  <description>
    <p>Mappero Geotagger is a geotagging application: it allows you to assign a
      geographic location to your photos. The location information is embedded
      following a standard format in the picture file itself, so that you won't
      lose it if you need to move the file around; and if you upload it to 
      Flickr or other services which support the EXIF standard, other people
      will be able to find your pictures just by browsing a map.</p>

    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Automatic downloading of maps from OpenStreetMap.</li>
      <li>Visualize existing location information by showing your photos on a map.</li>
      <li>Set or modify geolocation information by dragging pictures on the map.</li>
      <li>Visualization of GPX and KML GPS tracks.</li>
      <li>Automatic assignment of location information by correlating the time
        of the photos with the times of a GPX track (this process is often
        called <em>correlation</em>).</li>
      <li>Graphic visualization of the photos on the map during the GPX
        correlation operation, with controls to specify time zone offset and
        fine-grained time adjustment.</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Mappero Geotagger supports all file formats supported by libexiv2.</p>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The main screen</caption>
      <image>http://www.mardy.it/archivos/imagines/mappero-geotagger.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>See Mappero Geotagger in action</caption>
      <video>https://youtu.be/b1J84dISuNk</video>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">http://mappero.mardy.it/</url>

  <provides>
    <binary>mappero</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.6" date="2019-10-30">
      <description>
        <p>Accept items from command line, add MIME-type information</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7" date="2020-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>Improve help screen, add tooltips</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8" date="2020-04-15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Zooming with the mouse wheel now pivots on the mouse cursor</li>
          <li>Prevent the same files to be added twice in the same session</li>
          <li>Make HERE maps work again</li>
          <li>Avoid sub-pixel smoothing of map tiles: improves readability</li>
          <li>Set proper application icon for Linux window managers</li>
          <li>Update About page for new site links</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9" date="2020-04-23">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Handle pinch gesture for zooming</li>
          <li>Handle wheel events on the image list</li>
          <li>Increase the tile cache size to avoid issues on HighDPI displays</li>
          <li>Improve item centering and zooming when adding geotagged photos</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10" date="2020-09-22">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix a crash when loading certain DNG files</li>
          <li>Fix the Yandex Satellite map layer</li>
          <li>Add a notice in the Help screen if a new version is available</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
